

# STEFANOS LINTAS

Full Stack Developer

<u>LinkedIn</u> – stefanos.lidas@gmail.com

#### About me:

A full stack developer with 6+ years of professional experience in web app development using .Net Core, .Net Framework, Java MVC, DAO architecture, Rest, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Tomcat, Maven, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML5. Passionate for elegant code, responsive design and asynchronous loading to provide an excellent user experience. Working in parallel as a programming tutor for 5+ years on the above-mentioned technologies as well as Python, PostgreSQL, SOAP

## **WORKING EXPERIENCE:**

## **ATCOM**

# Feb. 2023 - Present (Remote)

#### **Full stack**

Working in the RND department implementing new features for ATCOM's main product "Netvolution". Netvolution is a CMS which has managed to achieve great success within the market.

The Languages we use are C# (.net core), MS-SQL, HTML, JS, jQuery, Sass (CSS). Additional noteworthy tools: Azure, Kubernetes, Kibana, Hang fire, Elastic, Gulp.

- Working on every part of Netvolution and its components
- Implementing the UI/UX's team templates and enabling them to have a multitude of data sources as well as functionality depending on the context and current state.
- Indexing data on elastic for Kibana and consumption for the app.
- Creating abstraction layers for easy integration of the CMS components according to each client's needs
- Optimizing page speed and critical rendering path. Besides the typical techniques such as minify, uglify etc. We use require.js to load only the necessary JS files for each component currently used.

# Vertitech – Classter

# Jan. 2022 – Feb. 2023 (Remote)

# Full stack developer

At Classter we were developing an online web application that provides a platform for the efficient management of learning institutions (LMS).

- Worked on the whole platform back to front as well as connecting and managing external service providers.
- External service integration. I was responsible for integrating and connecting Moodle into the Classter API.
- Entity framework and MS-SQL for the database

# My Style Town Oct. 2015 - Nov. 2020 (Hybrid UK, Greece)

# Full stack developer with more focus on the front end

My Style Town was a startup developing a web application to promote fashion designers. I was responsible for:

- Designing a drag and drop system (to create clothing sets) using HTML5,
   JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap to construct the initial layout.
- Writing code to batch the data into subsets and asynchronously loading them using AJAX and JSON, handling a very large load of data and thus providing a no latency experience for the user.
- Designed a system so the saved sets could be viewed and shown through our REST API.

# Programming Tutor 2016 – Present

Working as a programming tutor and providing guidance for Implementations of thesis for bachelor's and master's degrees.

"ER – Manager" (Emergency room manager for hospitals)

 Designed a web-based application that allows healthcare professionals to manage ER priorities based on a risk evaluation model of clinical factors upon admission, creating a priority list as well as relevant statistical data.

"Concurrent Implementations"

• Developed a thread manager in C to create, deploy and prune threads in order to design a web servlet from the ground up including rudimentary optimization techniques for the incoming queries such LRUs etc.

## **EDUCATION**

Technical University of Crete.

Department of Electronics and Computer Engineering (Meng 5-year program) (2009-2014)

Thesis: A web-based application to predict and calculate the projected load on an electric grid by a fleet of EVs

Developed a web application that uses the Google Maps API through Rest calls in order to calculate the additional load on the electric grid due to EV charging. Additional individual users could utilize the platform and get optimal pathing to their destination by taking into consideration their specific EV capabilities and availability of charging stations along their way.

# **SKILLS**

C#	• • • • •	JavaScript	• • • • •
Java	• • • • •	MySQL	• • • • •
ReactJS	• • • • •	CSS3	• • • • •
Kubernetes	• • • • •	HTML	• • • • •
LANGUAGES			
English	• • • •	Greek	• • • • •
French	• • • • •		
MILITARY	Military service completed		